<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://okjuan.github.io/journals/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://okjuan.github.io/journals/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-12T21:56:33+00:00</updated><id>https://okjuan.github.io/journals/feed.xml</id><title type="html">journals</title><entry><title type="html">honest mechanic</title><link href="https://okjuan.github.io/journals/honest-mechanic" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="honest mechanic" /><published>2023-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-12T21:55:24+00:00</updated><id>https://okjuan.github.io/journals/honest-mechanic</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://okjuan.github.io/journals/honest-mechanic"><![CDATA[<p>The two young guys standing at the counter had brought in a 2005 Honda Civic for a pre-purchase inspection and Amir had found several issues.
The two guys want a print-out of the inspection as proof so they can get on their way but Amir doesn’t want to give them anything with his shop’s name.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I fail inspections and then people give me bad reviews on Google. All the dealerships in this area hate me! That car right there is from the dealership. I drive it around and when it gets hot, it goes b-b-boom. They tell me, come on, just pass it. They tell me no, no, no, I say no, no, no.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The two guys smile and nod.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>A guy brought me a car that passed an inspection and I failed it! I called the guy and told him he’s lucky he brought it to me! I told him this, this, this, and you are lucky because they would take your license away. And he said oh thank you, thank you so much. Next day I see a bad review on Google. Ah you think I don’t know what that is?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>More silent nodding.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Because of my job, I have to be honest! If I pass the inspection, peoples lives depend on it, and they take the car out and – boom! They tell me to pass the inspection, but I have to be honest, I don’t care.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I wanna ask him whether he’s watched Seinfeld and tell him about the episode where Jerry agonizes over falling out with his mechanic, the only honest mechanic in New York.</p>

<p>When I’m up at the counter paying, I see a sign on the wall that says his shop has been “serving the community since 1997.”
I tell him I was one year old then.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>You were one year old? Now you are a man! And back then, I was like you! Now! I am old!</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="honesty" /><category term="car-salesmen" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The two young guys standing at the counter had brought in a 2005 Honda Civic for a pre-purchase inspection and Amir had found several issues. The two guys want a print-out of the inspection as proof so they can get on their way but Amir doesn’t want to give them anything with his shop’s name.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">young doctor on the plane</title><link href="https://okjuan.github.io/journals/young-doc" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="young doctor on the plane" /><published>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-12T21:55:24+00:00</updated><id>https://okjuan.github.io/journals/young.doctor.on.plane</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://okjuan.github.io/journals/young-doc"><![CDATA[<p>It seemed, until the very last moment, that the seat to my right would be empty.
But eventually it was taken by a slim white man in his thirties wearing a red t-shirt.
I was wearing noise cancelling headphones so I only noticed he was talking to me when he gestured at my laptop screen.</p>

<p>He didn’t know much about programming but had taken a course in university for easy credits.
Since then, he’d finished medical school and moved out from Ontario to a small city in BC to do his residency.
For a while he worked in an emergency room – that was the best way to learn.
He wanted to run a family practice now though.</p>

<p>He was going to Quebec to visit his girlfriend, who he was probably gonna marry.
They’d only been together for a couple of months, but they were on the path, he was feeling good about it.
He’d met her online on a Christian dating site and just met her for the first time a month ago.
It was a funny story actually, he proposed the first day they met.</p>

<p>He flew in to see her for the first time and she had said to him that he probably couldn’t stay quiet for even half an hour – it came up because she had just gone on a weekend silent meditation retreat and loved it – but she said he was so chatty that being quiet would be so hard for him, so he decided to pull a prank on her.
When he landed, she picked him up at the airport and said hi but he didn’t say anything back, he stayed quiet because she said he probably couldn’t.
He prepared a bunch of flash cards to tell her things so he wouldn’t have to talk, and it was sort of like a scavenger hunt and at the end he proposed.</p>

<p>She didn’t say no, she said not yet, but they were probably gonna get married.
They were quite complementary – she liked reading and didn’t really like outdoor stuff, and he liked to go camping and skiing and stuff like that.
He almost died actually, skiing in the backcountry.
He only survived because his friend was there, he saved his life.
Cracked his skull!
But they were quite complementary, he didn’t wanna say that she was his ticket to sainthood, but she would purify him.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="relationships" /><category term="marriage" /><category term="religion" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It seemed, until the very last moment, that the seat to my right would be empty. But eventually it was taken by a slim white man in his thirties wearing a red t-shirt. I was wearing noise cancelling headphones so I only noticed he was talking to me when he gestured at my laptop screen.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">first thursday at metier brewing</title><link href="https://okjuan.github.io/journals/metier-brewing" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="first thursday at metier brewing" /><published>2023-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-12T21:55:24+00:00</updated><id>https://okjuan.github.io/journals/first-thursday-at-metier-brewing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://okjuan.github.io/journals/metier-brewing"><![CDATA[<p><em>As Daudi Abe tells in his 2020 book,</em> <a href="https://uwapress.uw.edu/book/9780295747569/emerald-street/">Emerald Street: A History of Hip Hop in Seattle</a><em>, the city’s black folks first set down roots in Central District (the CD) in the late 1880s. After World War II, during the Second Great Migration, Seattle’s black population soared into the tens of thousands, 80% of which lived in the CD by the mid 1960s. In recent decades, the portion of black residents in the CD has declined due in part to gentrification. Nonetheless, the black community’s influence on the life of this neighborhood remains alive and well.</em></p>

<p>Cherry Street runs down one of Seattle’s many hills, past <a href="https://www.206zulu.org/">206 Zulu</a> headquarters at Washington Hall, up another hill, and down again into a cluster of Ethiopian restaurants and other black-owned businesses. Among them is Seattle’s first black-owned brewery, Métier Brewing Community Taproom, which opened last summer here in the CD, which <a href="https://metierbrewing.com/locations/cherry-street/">Métier calls</a> “the heart and soul of Black Seattle”.</p>

<p>I had never heard of Métier Brewing when my friends called to invite me down. They had come to Métier for a drink and found a jazz trio performing for free. It sounded good over the phone. I arrived in time to catch only one song before the band took a break. I recognized the tune, but couldn’t remember what it was. Masego, maybe? While I ordered an IPA and a kimchi pork <em>okazu pan</em> at the bar, I got a chance to ask the keyboard player, Brandon J. Young. The song was Footprints by Wayne Shorter, the jazz giant who passed away that very day at the age of 89. I realized later that I recognized it from Madlib’s Shades of Blue, an instrumental hip hop album assembled from the archives of Blue Note jazz records.</p>

<p>On the way back to my table, I passed a wall emblazoned with the brewery’s promise: <strong>Brew Damn Good Beer, Build Stronger Community, Inspire Bigger Dreams For Everyone</strong>. In keeping with their mission statement, Métier had recently partnered with NW Folklife to offer free live music every first Thursday, and this month’s artist was the Chris Patin Band (pronounced Pot-tan). The trio’s drummer and leader had attended high school down the street at Garfield High thirty or so years ago and played in their winning Jazz Combo. Longer ago, Garfield’s jazz program educated a young Quincy Jones.</p>

<p>Soon, the band settled back behind their instruments for the second half of the set, this time joined by a singer and Freddy ‘Fuego’ Gonzalez on trombone. Freddy introduced the singer and warned us we didn’t know what we were in for. It was clear mere seconds into “Feeling Good” that Freddy wasn’t talking her up. Here was not only a talented singer but a performer with a presence befitting a stage the size of this whole taproom. And yet here she was singing mere feet from the wooden benches where we sat drinking. Singing for free, for the community.</p>

<p>Next, the band launched into a version of “Fever” infused with a Buena Vista Social Club-style rhythm. The singer swayed and stepped as she sang, but the small crowd was too shy to be beckoned up onto their feet. I grooved in my seat, head bopping, foot bouncing. The song ended but the singer hadn’t given up on us. As the band started playing the slow, unmistakable intro to “Stand By Me”, the singer started recruiting dancers one by one.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>And you, you’re bopping your head, that means you have rhythm.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>She lined the four of us up side by side as the intro came to an end.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Just dance til your soul is happy!… <strong>When the night… has come…</strong></p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="seattle" /><category term="central-district" /><category term="live-music" /><category term="brewery" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Daudi Abe tells in his 2020 book, Emerald Street: A History of Hip Hop in Seattle, the city’s black folks first set down roots in Central District (the CD) in the late 1880s. After World War II, during the Second Great Migration, Seattle’s black population soared into the tens of thousands, 80% of which lived in the CD by the mid 1960s. In recent decades, the portion of black residents in the CD has declined due in part to gentrification. Nonetheless, the black community’s influence on the life of this neighborhood remains alive and well.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">speakeasy</title><link href="https://okjuan.github.io/journals/speakeasy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="speakeasy" /><published>2022-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-12T21:55:24+00:00</updated><id>https://okjuan.github.io/journals/speakeasy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://okjuan.github.io/journals/speakeasy"><![CDATA[<p>As we are finishing our meals, the waiter comes over. It’s not to ask us anything, but to bless us with the news that we have completed our time in purgatory and earned our time to ascend. The speakeasy awaits.</p>

<p>I pick up the faux-phone hanging in the middle of the dining area and after three brief tones I hear a woman’s voice: <em>What’s the password?</em> I read out the phrase from the scrap of paper. The door is hefty and swings smoothly like it’s guarding a vault. We step inside, shutting out the sunlight and the lesser patrons behind us. We climb up a steep, jagged set of stairs lined with pristine wood paneling and framed pictures. It’s so new I can smell traces of the contractor’s cologne.</p>

<p>We come out to a lounge lit warm and dim. Although we’d been told to wait for space to open up, the place is mostly empty. We figure a party of ten or twenty has just slipped out of the unmarked doorway at the bottom of the stairs, which leads conveniently onto the avenue sidewalk. We hesitate, then we see we are being beckoned. Stepping gingerly up to the bar, we are aware that our demeanor is crucial to the integrity of the vibe. We try not to speak too loudly, or act too casually. Ambience is a delicate affair.</p>

<p>We sit at the bar, where the young bartender distills the complex world of flavor into a four-tile matrix. He writes it in pen on the back of a coaster. The lack of menu is presumably an authentic vestige of the prohibition years, when evidence couldn’t be risked. The bartender doesn’t need recipes, anyway. My friend reveals his preferences and I do mine. The bartender then relaxes and opens himself to the inspiration in the air. It’s like watching Keith Jarrett playing live in Köln. There are windows looking over the restaurant downstairs but I dare not peer down lest I break the spell.</p>

<p>This young man, so young, is already at the helm. Perhaps he is back home from theatre school for the summer and has found here a worthy use for his talents of performance and improvisation. And here I am, front row seat, witnessing it all. I can only imagine how quickly his mind is working. Hmm, yes, ok, some of this… and perhaps some of this… and, hm, let me think… ah, how about this… ok, very good… but we’re missing something… Ah yes, a floral note! Let’s go for the jugular — an actual flower, plucked out of the fridge, and dropped delicately on top… It might seem pointless but it is for the drinker to taste <em>psychologically</em>, as an after-thought, as it were, as he rises from the misting surface of his libation.</p>

<p>My friend takes his drink gratefully, eager to taste this fresh creation. And now the bartender turns to me. His untamed curls fall gracefully over one eye as he confirms my preferences, and once again his mind begins its sweep through the possibilities, in search of the optimal triangulation that would locate my desires in the world of spirits. I sense a certain shakiness in him — I must not mistake it for a wavering confidence but identify it as the tremble of excitement one must feel as spontaneous creation rushes out. His arms bounce at his sides as he shakes the mixture, moving with the sureness of one born with maracas in hand. Perhaps he’s not a theatre student but studying percussion.</p>

<p>I receive my drink and take a hesitant sip. It is my role to crown the achievement and I don’t want to let him down. Genius can be so fragile. But I am relieved from my responsibility — the drink is good.</p>

<p>I suggest to my friend that we retire to the sofa, which has freed up. But my friend knows better. He looks at the bartender, who confirms that yes, it is reserved. Ah, well that explains the emptiness all around! Here I was thinking that it made sense for it be quiet on a Tuesday at 7pm, but no, the apparent lull in business is, in fact, the peak of exclusivity!</p>

<p>So we enjoy our drinks at the bar, and a man sitting by himself nearby engages in some light delightful chat about Louis XIV with the bartender, who gleefully remarks: <em>Ha ha! Louis XIV!</em> They then move on to a topic that resonates even more deeply and thus draws a personal confession: <em>Ah, nostalgia.. I live for that stuff.</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="seattle" /><category term="cocktail-bar" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As we are finishing our meals, the waiter comes over. It’s not to ask us anything, but to bless us with the news that we have completed our time in purgatory and earned our time to ascend. The speakeasy awaits.]]></summary></entry></feed>